let questions = [
    {
        "question": "Welche Klöße schmecken Fritz am besten?",
        "option1": "Wiener Klöße",
        "option2": "Bayrische Klöße",
        "option3": "Thüringer Klöße",
        "option4": "Frankfurter Klöße",
        "rightAnswer": "3",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "Was ist den mit ......... los?",
        "option1": "Jürgen",
        "option2": "Thomas",
        "option3": "Helmut",
        "option4": "Karsten",
        "rightAnswer": "4",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "wer ist der wasch echter Isländer?",
        "option1": "Henry Henrissohn",
        "option2": "sein Bruder Jürgen Hurensohn",
        "option3": "David Gudjohnsohn",
        "option4": "Björn Bjorensohn",
        "rightAnswer": "2",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "wer ist von den 4 hier ! nicht ! am Samstag für die fette Party dabei?",
        "option1": "Safari",
        "option2": "Patrick",
        "option3": "UWE",
        "option4": "Gundula :D",
        "rightAnswer": "4",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "was hat Walter Frosch versucht Jahre lang zu machen?",
        "option1": "versucht sauber und fair zu spielen",
        "option2": "versucht die Kippe aus Mund weg zu halten",
        "option3": "in der schnelle eine durchziehen",
        "option4": "eeee keine Ahnung!",
        "rightAnswer": "1",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "Was sagt ein Gen, wenn es ein anderes trifft?",
        "option1": "moin na du?",
        "option2": "Halogen",
        "option3": "moinsen",
        "option4": "ciao papito",
        "rightAnswer": "2",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "Egal, wie gut du schläfst: Albert schläft wie...",
        "option1": "Zweistein",
        "option2": "ein Block",
        "option3": "Einstein",
        "option4": "drei Steine vielleicht?",
        "rightAnswer": "3",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "Was hat vier Beine und kann fliegen?",
        "option1": "Zwei Vögel",
        "option2": "einer der Red Bull rein knallt!",
        "option3": "ja du vielleicht! wenn du besoffen bist :D",
        "option4": "brudi muss los keine Ahnung",
        "rightAnswer": "1",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "Wie lautet der Vorname vom Reh?",
        "option1": "Reh-Reh",
        "option2": "Kartoffelpü",
        "option3": "reh-reh aber klein geschrieben",
        "option4": "....",
        "rightAnswer": "2",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "Welche Schuhe tragen BILD-Redakteure?",
        "option1": "Crocs",
        "option2": "Flip-Flops",
        "option3": "Yeezys",
        "option4": "Skandalen",
        "rightAnswer": "4",
        "category": "deutsche Meme & Flachwitze",
    },
    {
        "question": "who invented HTML?",
        "option1": "Lady GaGa",
        "option2": "Tim Berners-Lee",
        "option3": "Dr. Frankenstein",
        "option4": "Steve Jobs",
        "rightAnswer": "2",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "who invented the Linux OS?",
        "option1": "Linus Malte",
        "option2": "Ken Thompson",
        "option3": "Brendan Eich",
        "option4": "Linus Torvalds",
        "rightAnswer": "4",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "who are the founders of GooGle?",
        "option1": "Sundar Pichai",
        "option2": "Satya Nadella",
        "option3": "Larry Page and Sergey Brin",
        "option4": "Anne Wojcicki",
        "rightAnswer": "3",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "which Programming language is the easiest to learn at the beginning of a programmer career?",
        "option1": "Python",
        "option2": "C++",
        "option3": "Swift",
        "option4": "just pick a language and stick to it untill you grasp at least 40% of it :) ",
        "rightAnswer": "4",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "which programming language does NASA predominantly use?",
        "option1": "HAL/S",
        "option2": "JS Vanilla",
        "option3": "Python & C#",
        "option4": "English",
        "rightAnswer": "1",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "how do programmers count?",
        "option1": "1 - 2 - 3 - 4 - 5...",
        "option2": "duhh.. like a normal human being!",
        "option3": "0 - 1 - 2 - 3 - 4 - 5...",
        "option4": "0 - 1 - 0 - 1 - 0 - 1...",
        "rightAnswer": "3",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "how do programmers work most of their time?",
        "option1": "blame others for their bugs!",
        "option2": "they google and search in Stackoverflow 80% of their time",
        "option3": "they go outside their house for a walk or some activity",
        "option4": "they get asked to help 'resetting WiFi Password' or 'hack facbook account'",
        "rightAnswer": "2",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "what is the best Method to fix and overcome 'BUGS'?",
        "option1": "using chemicals like Acid and Sulfur",
        "option2": "Raid ",
        "option3": "leaving the House and never coming back!",
        "option4": "use the Debugger",
        "rightAnswer": "4",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "who invented Python?",
        "option1": "Guido van Rossum",
        "option2": "Yukihiro Matsumoto",
        "option3": "David Flanagan",
        "option4": "Dennis Ritchie",
        "rightAnswer": "1",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
    {
        "question": "who invented RUBY?",
        "option1": "James Gosling",
        "option2": "Bjarne Stroustrup",
        "option3": "Yukihiro Matsumoto",
        "option4": "Herb Sutter",
        "rightAnswer": "3",
        "category": "Programieren",
    },
];
let filteredCategory = [];
let currentQuestion = 0;
let rightAnswer = 0;


function startGame() {
    document.getElementById('mainCard').classList.remove('d-none');
    document.getElementById('categories').classList.add('d-none');

}